[SPEAKER_00]: Two young friends, Min and Hai, each received a seed from their teacher.
[SPEAKER_00]: The teacher said, whoever grows the most beautiful plant in six months will receive a great reward.
[SPEAKER_00]: Min cared for his seed daily, watering it, adding fertilizer, and placing it in the sunlight.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hai, however, tucked his seed into a drawer and did nothing.
[SPEAKER_00]: He thought, I'll just buy a beautiful plant from the market, why bother growing it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Six months later, Min brought a vibrant, blooming plant with lush leaves.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hai presented an expensive purchased plant, its roots still caked with nursery soil.
[SPEAKER_00]: The teacher pointed to Min's plant and said, the reward is yours.
[SPEAKER_00]: Life does not value deceit.
[SPEAKER_00]: True happiness grows from sincere effort, just like the seed you nurtured.
[SPEAKER_00]: Lasting success comes from patience and honesty.
[SPEAKER_00]: Never seek shortcuts, what you gain through deception, life will take away in other ways.