I once walked into a cafe with a barista who greeted every customer with a smile, even
the ones who didn't smile back.
An old man dropped his change, and a teenager nearby helped him pick it up without being
asked.
A woman held the door for a mother juggling a stroller and three bags.
None of them knew each other, but respect was flowing like quiet magic.
That day, I realized respect isn't just about grand gestures.
It's in the small unseen things.
It's in listening without interrupting, even if you disagree.
It's in thanking the janitor as much as the CEO.
It's in not laughing when someone mispronounces a word, because it means they learned it
by reading.
The more I gave respect, the more it circled back.
Even on bad days, I tried to remember that everyone's carrying something I can't see.
And when I treated others with dignity, I felt lighter too.
But I learned it doesn't cost a thing, but it changes everything.
Thank you.